Guide to the United States Army School of Military Aeronautics at Cornell University records, 1917-1919.
United States Army School of Military Aeronautics at Cornell University records,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
United States Army School of Military Aeronautics at Cornell University records, 1917-1919.
33-2-110
United States. School of Military Aeronautics at Cornell University
12.4 cubic ft.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, financial reports, curricula, inventories, photographs, weekly reports, lists of students, subject files, and other records of the School at Cornell University. Includes registrar cards for students. Photographs include composites, Cornell University cadets during training maneuvers held at Enfield Glen, Tompkins County, New York. Includes a picture of Ray June of Ithaca, New York wearing a World War I uniform. Also, a glass plate positive of an aerial view of a stadium, possibly at Cornell University, taken by Donald H. Ellison in 1917 or 1918. Also two volumes, one the History of the United States Army School of Military Aeronautics at Cornell including photographs, charts, examinations, booklets, and other material compiled and another 12 leaf volume titled Air Service history of Cornell University November 24, 1919 containing a brief typewritten history of activities in connection with the Air Service in World War I at Cornell University, including the School of Military Aeronautics, the School of Aerial Photography, and contributions of departments and individuals. It includes lists of Cornell flying aces and Cornell casualties of aerial combat. Photographs of Barton Hall glued in, showing how it was used for student quarters, laboratories, and airplane storage both these volumes compiled by Professor William Nichols Barnard who served as President of the Academic Board of the U. S. Army School of Military Aeronautics at Cornell. Also a bound manuscript, 241 leaves, titled History of the United States Army School of Military Aeronautics at Cornell University, Ithaca, N.Y., May 1917 to December 1918 by Charles Beverley Benson instructor at the school. Volume includes a detailed typewritten history of the School of Military Aeronautics, with many photographs and samples of forms glued in. It also includes lists of School students and staff and Cornell flying aces. Also a notebook from the School of Military Aeronautics at Cornell University, March, 1918 compiled by George V. Murphy. Also an album with photographs by John P. Troy that includes images of Barton Hall airplane laboratory.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, financial reports, curricula, inventories, photographs, weekly reports, lists of students, subject files, and other records of the School at Cornell University. Includes registrar cards for students. Photographs include composites, Cornell University cadets during training maneuvers held at Enfield Glen, Tompkins County, New York. Includes a picture of Ray June of Ithaca, New York wearing a World War I uniform. Also, a glass plate positive of an aerial view of a stadium, possibly at Cornell University, taken by Donald H. Ellison in 1917 or 1918. Also two volumes, one the History of the United States Army School of Military Aeronautics at Cornell including photographs, charts, examinations, booklets, and other material compiled and another 12 leaf volume titled Air Service history of Cornell University November 24, 1919 containing a brief typewritten history of activities in connection with the Air Service in World War I at Cornell University, including the School of Military Aeronautics, the School of Aerial Photography, and contributions of departments and individuals. It includes lists of Cornell flying aces and Cornell casualties of aerial combat. Photographs of Barton Hall glued in, showing how it was used for student quarters, laboratories, and airplane storage both these volumes compiled by Professor William Nichols Barnard who served as President of the Academic Board of the U. S. Army School of Military Aeronautics at Cornell. Also a bound manuscript, 241 leaves, titled History of the United States Army School of Military Aeronautics at Cornell University, Ithaca, N.Y., May 1917 to December 1918 by Charles Beverley Benson instructor at the school. Volume includes a detailed typewritten history of the School of Military Aeronautics, with many photographs and samples of forms glued in. It also includes lists of School students and staff and Cornell flying aces. Also a notebook from the School of Military Aeronautics at Cornell University, March, 1918 compiled by George V. Murphy. Also an album with photographs by John P. Troy that includes images of Barton Hall airplane laboratory.
SUBJECTS
Names:
United States.; Barnard, William N. (William Nichols), 1875-1947; Benson, Charles Beverley; June, Ray, 1898-1958.; Murphy, George V.; June, Ray, 1898-1958; Ellison, Donald H.; Barton Hall (Cornell University); Cornell University -- History.; Cornell University; Cornell University. School of Aerial Photography.; Cornell University -- Students.; United States Army.; United States. School of Military Aeronautics at Cornell University.; United States. Army; Cornell University; World War (1914-1918)
Subjects:
Aeronautics, Military -- Ithaca.; Aeronautics -- United States.; Aeronautics military -- Study and teaching; Aerial photography.; Fighter pilots -- Training of -- United States.; Military education.; Military readiness.; Physical education and training, Military.; World War, 1914-1918 -- Aerial operations, American.; World War, 1914-1918.; Aeronautics, Military -- Study and teaching; Military education; Military participation -- American; Military readiness; Physical education and training, Military; Students; World War, 1914-1918 -- Participation, American.
Places:
Enfield (N.Y.); New York (State) -- Ithaca
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Pictorial works
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
CONTAINER LIST
- World War I Weekly Reports - Aaronson to Campfield, 1917-1918; Item number (Box 1, Folder Folder)
  Cards with photographs, demographic information and weekly reports
- World War I Weekly Reports - Canaday to Evitt, 1917-1918 (Box 2)
- World War I Weekly Reports - Fagan to Marsden, 1917-1918 (Box 3)
- World War I Weekly Reports- Marsh to Parker, 1917-1918 (Box 4)
  Cards with photographs, demographic information and weekly reports (some cards in need of preservation)
- World War I Weekly Reports- Parker to Sexton, 1917-1918 (Box 5)
- World War I Weekly Reports- Seymour to Ware, 1917-1918 (Box 6)
- Signalling Tests and Papers, 1917-1918 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Destroyed photographs in folder
- Military Papers, 1917-1918 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Gunnery Papers and Correspondence, 1917-1918 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Gunnery Papers and Correspondence, 1917-1918 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Airplane-Related Notes and Correspondence, 1917-1918 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Observations, Reports, and Memoranda, 1917-1918 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous Papers, 1917-1918 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Progress Reports, 1917-1918 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Financial Reports, 1917-1918 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Financial Reports, 1917-1918 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Tuition Reports, 1917-1918 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Correspondence Regarding Academic Appointments, 1917-1918 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous Papers, 1917-1918 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Personnel Reports, 1917-1918 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Curriculum Reports and Blueprint, 1917-1918 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Curriculum Reports, 1917-1918 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- World War I Weekly Reports- Ware to Zuckerman, 1917-1918 (Box 8)
- Regular Reports, 1918 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Examining Board, 1917-1918 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Examinations, 1917-1918 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Photos to Washington, 1917-1918 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Supplies Equipment- Inventories, 1917-1918 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Statistics, 1917-1918 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Instructions for Faculty and Clerks, 1917-1918 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Academic Board, 1917-1918 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Engineers' Course Marks-Schedules, 1917-1918 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Inventories, 1918-09 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- School of Aerial Photography Order Forms and Correspondence, 1917-1918 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Notes on Canadian Course (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Tuition Due, Expression (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Tuition Due, 1918-01-1918-05 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Tuition Due, 1918-07-1918-10 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Curriculum-Revised, 1918-03-01 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Curriculum-Revised, 1918-03-01 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Correspondence Record-President of Academic Board USA School of Military Aeronautics, 1917-11-30-1918-11-26 (Box 9)
  Monograph
- Announcement of War-Time Courses, 1917 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Correspondence and Photo, 1912-1918 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  Photograph of Carl E. Erngstrom-1912 inside
- Blank Forms and Course Information, 1917-1918 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- United States Army School of Military Aeronautics Bulletins, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- United States Army School of Military Aeronautics Bulletins, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Correspondence From President of the Academic Board and Financial Information, 1917-1918 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1917 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Receiving Room Invoices, 1918-01-11-1918-11-23 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, Invoices, and Price Lists, 1917-1918 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Correspondence and Invoices, 1917-1918 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Correspondence Concerning Buildings and Grounds, Postcard, and Invoices, 1917-1918 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Comptroller and Treasurer Correspondence, 1917-1919 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Administrative Correspondence and Photography School Correspondence, 1917-1919 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Memorandums and Correspondence, 1917-1918 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Invoices, Correspondence, and Instructions for Instructors and Heads of Departments, 1917-1918 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- General Correspondence, 1917-1918 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- General Correspondence, Invoices, and Office of Director of Military Aeronautics Correspondence, 1917-1918 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- General Correspondence and Financial Information, 1917-1918 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Financial Statements, 1917-10-31-1918-10-07 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- General Correspondence, 1917-1918 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Chief Signalling Officer Correspondence, 1917-1918 (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Commandant Correspondence, Memoranda, and Bulletins, 1917-1918 (Box 9, Folder 22)
- General Correspondence and Invoices, 1917-1918 (Box 9, Folder 23)
- General Correspondence, 1917-1918 (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Correspondence Chief Signal Officer of the Army, 1917-11-09 (Box 9, Folder 25)
- World War I Weekly Reports- Ahrens to Starquist, 1918 (Box 10)
- World War I Weekly Reports- Stein to Young, 1918 (Box 11)
- Class of July 21, 1917- Aug 4, 1917 Weekly Reports, 1917-07-21-1917-08-04 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Class of Aug 18, 1917- Sept 01, 1917 Weekly Reports, 1917-08-18-1917-09-01 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Class of Sept 15, 1917- Sept 29, 1917 Weekly Reports, 1917-09-15-1917-09-29 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Class of Oct 13, 1917- Oct 20, 1917 Weekly Reports, 1917-10-13-1917-10-20 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Class of Oct 27, 1917-Nov 10, 1917 Weekly Reports, 1917-10-27-1917-11-10 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Class of Nov 3, 1917- Nov 17, 1917 Weekly Reports, 1917-11-03-1917-11-17 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Class of Dec 01, 1917- Dec 22, 1917 Weekly Reports, 1917-12-01-1917-12-22 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Class of January 12, 1918 Weekly Reports, 1917-11-10-1918-01-12 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Class of January 19, 1918 Weekly Reports, 1917-11-17-1918-01-19 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Class of January 26, 1918 Weekly Reports, 1917-11-24-1918-01-26 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Class of February 2, 1918 Weekly Reports, 1917-12-01-1918-02-02 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Class of February 16, 1918 Weekly Reports I and II, 1917-12-15-1918-02-16 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Class of February 23, 1918 Weekly Reports I and II, 1918-02-09-1918-02-23 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Class of March 2, 1918 Weekly Reports, 1918-01-12-1918-03-02 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Class of March 9, 1918 Weekly Reports, 1918-01-19-1918-03-09 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Class of March 16, 1918 Weekly Reports, 1918-03-16 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Class of March 23, 1918 Weekly Reports, 1918-03-23 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Class of March 30, 1918 Weekly Reports, 1918-03-30 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Squadron N. Engineers Weekly Reports, 1917-12-22-1918-01-19 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Regulations Pamphlets, 1918 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  Belonging to Cadet Walter H. Stainton
- School of Military Aeronautics Weekly Reports, 1917-10-06-1917-11-26 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- School of Military Aeronautics Weekly Reports, 1917-10-20-1917-12-08 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- School of Military Aeronautics Weekly Reports, 1917-10-27-1917-12-15 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Class of February 9, 1918 Weekly Reports- Sergeant A to Sg. D, 1917-12-02-1918-02-09 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Class of February 9, 1918 Weekly Reports- Sergeant F to Sg. H, 1918-01-19-1918-02-09 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Class of April 6, 1918 Weekly Reports, 1918-02-13-1918-04-06 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Class of April 13, 1918 Weekly Reports, 1918-02-23-1918-04-13 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Class of April 20, 1918 Weekly Reports, 1918-03-02-1918-04-20 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Class of April 27, 1918 Weekly Reports I and II, 1918-03-09-1918-04-27 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Class of May 4, 1918- June 1, 1918 Weekly Reports: Squadrons I-40-B, I-40-C, K-40, K-41-A, L-41-A, 1918-05-04-1918-06-01 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Class of May 18, 1918- June 1, 1918 Weekly Reports, 1918-05-18-1918-06-01 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Class of June 8, 1918 Weekly Reports Squadrons A-M, 1918-03-23-1918-06-08 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Class of June 15, 1918 Weekly Reports Squadrons A-M, 1918-03-30-1918-06-15 (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Class of June 22, 1918 Weekly Reports, 1918-04-06-1918-06-22 (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Class of June 29, 1918 Weekly Reports, 1918-04-13-1918-06-29 (Box 12, Folder 16)
- Class of July 13, 1918 Weekly Reports Squadrons A-M, 1918-04-27-1918-07-13 (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Clas of July 20, 1918- July 27, 1918 Weekly Reports, 1918-05-20-1918-07-27 (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Class of August 3, 1918 Weekly Reports A-M, 1918-05-18-1918-08-03 (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Class of August 10, 1918 Weekly Reports A-M, 1918-05-25-1918-08-10 (Box 12, Folder 20)
- Class of August 17, 1918 Weekly Reports A-M, 1918-06-01-1918-08-17 (Box 12, Folder 21)
- Class of August 24, 1918 Weekly Reports Squadrons A-M, 1918-06-08-1918-08-24 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Class of August 31, 1918 Weekly Reports Squadrons A-M, 1918-06-15-1918-08-31 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Class of September 7, 1918 Weekly Reports Squadrons A-M, 1918-06-22-1918-09-08 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Class of September 14, 1918 Weekly Reports Squadrons A-M, 1918-06-29-1918-09-14 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Class of September 21, 1918 Weekly Reports A-M, 1918-07-06-1918-09-21 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Class of September 28, 1918 Weekly Reports A-M, 1918-07-03-1918-09-28 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Class Graduating Weekly Reports October 5, 1918 A-M, 1918-07-20-1918-10-05 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Class of October 12, 1918 Weekly Reports A-M, 1918-07-27-1918-10-12 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Class of October 19 and 26, 1918 Weekly Reports A-M, 1918-08-03-1918-10-26 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Class of November 2, 9, 13, 16, and 26, 1918 Weekly Reports A-E, 1918-11-02-1918-11-26 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Class of November 11 and 23, 1918 Sqs A-M, 1918-08-17-1918-11-23 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Class of November 23, 1918 Weekly Reports A-D, 1918-11-02-1918-11-23 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Photograph album of School of Military Aeronautics- Photographs 10-31 of Drill Hall in Barton Hall, 1918; Troy, John P.; 25.5 x 34 cm (Box 15)
  Gelatin silver prints
  Photograph albums
- Photographs of soldiers in camp, 1918; 7.4 x 12.5 cm; Photographs mounted on loose album pages. (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Photographs of buildings and soldiers in Ithaca, Watertown, 1918; 7.4 x 12.5 cm; Photographs mounted on loose album pages. (Box 13, Folder 14)
- History of the United States Army School of Military Aeronautics at Cornell University By CB Benson including Photograph Album, 1917-05-1918-12 (Box 14)
  Monograph, Very fragile condition
- Homework or Notes Concerning Military Equipment, 1917-1918 (Box 13, Folder 15)
- Aerial exposure glass positive of Cornell University Stadium, 1917-1918; Ellison, Donald H.; 16.5 x 21.5 cm (Box 15)
- United States Army School of Military Aeronautics at Cornell University Class of January 26, 1918 Class Photograph, 1918-01-26; 27 x 35.4 cm (Box Ms, Folder 1)
  Additional names listed verso.
- United States Army School of Military Aeronautics at Cornell University Class of February 2, 1918 Class Photograph, 1918-02-02; 27 x 35.4 cm (Box Ms, Folder 1)
- United States Army School of Military Aeronautics at Cornell University Class of March 2, 1918 Class Photograph, 1918-03-02; 27 x 35.4 cm (Box Ms, Folder 1)
- History of the United States Army School of Military Aeronautics at Cornell University By CB Benson, Monograph, Gift of President Schurman, circa 1919 (Volume Bd. Ms. 1)
- Air Service History of Cornell University by W.N. Barnard, Monograph, Gift of Professor W.N. Barnard., 1919-11-24 (Volume Bd. Ms. 2)